Hey, Its me Goofy!!
Today we are going to talk about earth globe
A globe is a spherical model of Earth, of some other celestial body, or of the celestial sphere.
Globes serve similar purposes to maps but unlike maps, do not distort the surface that they portray except to scale it down.
A globe of Earth is called a terrestrial globe. A globe of the celestial sphere is called a celestial globe.
A globe shows details of its subject. A terrestrial globe shows land masses and water bodies.
It might show nations and prominent cities and the network of latitude and longitude lines. Some have raised relief to show mountains.
A celestial globe shows stars, and may also show positions of other prominent astronomical objects.
Video created by Durgesh!!